Joshua Richards

Software Engineer

Email: jmrichards96@gmail.com Cell: (860) 951-6629

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/j-richards

Digital Resume: www.jrichards.space

Address: 153 Greystone Ln, Apt 12

Rochester, NY 14618

Summary

I am a full stack (primarily front-end) developer with experience ranging from web APIs to embedded systems. I have a passion for learning new technologies to implement projects both effectively and efficiently.

Skills

Technologies: JavaScript/TypeScript, ES6, Node.js, React JS, CSS, HTML, C#, C++, Git

- Ability to handle numerous responsibilities and desire to learn required skills
- Experience working in an agile development environment, implementing project features over a series of iterations within a release cycle

Experience

Carrier Global Corporation

Pittsford, NY

Software Engineer

Aug 27, 2018 - Present

- Responsible for the development of a web-based video streaming interface for security applications (with technologies including ES6, TypeScript, Node.js, RxJS, WebSockets)
- Responsible for development work on a SaaS security application that uses the streaming interface mentioned above (with technologies including Node.js, React, Redux)
- Utilizing services such as Rally, GitHub, Jenkins (CI/CD), and Azure
- Technical lead from January, 2020 to August, 2020
- Team lead from May, 2021 to Present. Responsibilities include:
 - Work with product management to plan features and define acceptance criteria
 - Define all stories/tasks for a feature
 - Run daily stand up and retrospective meetings
 - Give feature demos to product management and broader audience

Gerber Technology

Tolland, CT

Software Engineering Intern

June 4, 2018 – Aug 10, 2018

 Responsible for the development of a variety of safety enhancements to a material spreading system (with C++)

EagleDream Technologies

Rochester, NY

Web Developer Co-op

Aug 28, 2017 – Dec 15, 2017

 Responsible for the development of various fit for purpose websites (with technologies including JavaScript, C#, SQL, CSS, Sass, WordPress, Shopify, PHP)

Gerber Technology

Tolland, CT

Software Engineering Intern

June 5, 2017 - Aug 11, 2017

 Responsible for the development of a material cutting system's label printing interface (with C#, XAML, SQL, WPF)

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

Rochester, NY

Bachelor of Science in Game Design and Development

May 2019

Minor in Computer Science

GPA: 3.58